[ wind whispering ]
[ wind blowing ]
[ man ] A long , long time ago , Nosferatu , the undead ,
the race of the vampire , were driven from Egypt .
Most fled to the Carpathian Mountains of Transylvania ,
but others of better taste , including myself ,
traveled south through Africa and over the Atlantic
to a beautiful island hidden deep in the Bermuda Triangle .
There we lived for happy centuries feasting on the blood of unwary travelers
until discovered by the hunters once again .
Then the blood that spilled was our own .
[ unearthly shriek ]
I alone escaped , but a vampire alone is a vampire doomed .
My only chance was to find the one known offspring of our tribe
that had been born in a foreign land .
A woman somewhere in this place called Brooklyn .
[ people applauding ]
[ announcer ] Family Feud brings you
the world 's first coast-to-coast war of the showgirls .
Atlantic City vs. Las Vegas .
Here 's my show . Come on , baby . You make me excited .
" Name something a playboy might have made out of silk . "
[ buzzer warbling ]
Sheets , baby . Sheets .
- She ain 't gonna get it . - Why don 't you put me down for ten
on the Knickerbockers this weekend .
Ooh ! You betting on the Knicks . When will you learn ?
Call me , baby . Call Silas . I 'll take you to get your eight-piece special .
Sheets , baby . Come on , baby , sheets .
You make me excited . Okay , baby . Come on , now .
- C-H-E-E-T . Sheets . - Sheets .
- Yes . That 's what I 'm talking about . - Oh , shit . Sheets . The bitch said it .
Let me see ... " sheets . "
What is that ? What was that ?
Quake . What is this ? Earthquake .
This ain 't no earthquake . This is New York , fool .
What the fuck was that ?
- Oh , shit . - What the fuck is going on ?
Oh , shit . What the hell is that thing ?
Is this how people come and drive up in your shit ?
- Disrespecting your shit , man ? - Ain 't that a bitch .
What the ...
It 's a bird .
Get the hell away from me . Good God .
What the hell 's happening here ?
Damn .
Look at this ugly thing .
Who the hell 's piloting this vessel ? Stevie fucking Wonder ?
Must be a DUI . I don 't see no lights .
I don 't see no people either .
Damn . Look at the time .
I gotta bounce , Unc , I 'm supposed to be at my lady 's crib .
- Julius , bring your ass back here . - What ?
I don 't know nothing . My job is running numbers .
Your job is checking out spooky-ass ships .
- Go ahead with your bad self . - Chump .
Oh , I 'm not supposed to be scared , huh ?
Ahoy , there . Hello .
Ahoy , motherfucker .
Son of a bitch .
[ thunderclap ]
[ rain pattering ]
Oh , you 're the silent type , huh ?
Well , somebody 's going to buy me a new TV .
Fifty-inch color .
Shit . Oh , damn .
Ahoy , there .
You in there , somebody ?
Is this a joke ?
Ahoy .
Arrogant motherfuckers in here don 't want to say nothing .
Shit . I 'm too old for this shit . Ahoy .
Hello .
[ screaming ]
Help me ! Help me ! Help me !
Help me . Help , somebody . Help me . Help me .
Help me . Help me .
[ deep , guttural snarling ]
[ screams ]
[ gasping ]
That sure as hell wasn 't Lassie 's ass . Big motherfucker .
Jesus , Mary , and Jo-Jo .
Jesus , Mary and Jo-Jo .
Get the hell out of here .
Don 't even think about bringing your nappy black ass back here .
My Adidas . What ... Damn , baby , what 'd I do ?
- You were snoring . - Woman , everybody snores .
Not while they fucking !
- [ laughing ] - Piece of trash .
Eva , Eva , come back here . I was resting .
Rest this .
You gonna be begging for me back here tomorrow . That 's all right .
- Yeah , she 's gonna be begging . - That 's Julius .
- He owes him money too . - Yeah , I see him .
Oh , shit . Pizza man .
[ tires squealing ]
- Oh , shit . Coming through . - [ horns honking ]
- I 'll kill you . You better run , Julius . - [ tires screeching ]
I 'm coming after you .
Run , baby . Run .
I 'm coming after you , baby . Yeah .
Hey , get off my hood , man .
You mind if I borrow your hat ?
- No . Go ahead . - Thank you .
Hey . Hey , come on . Hey .
Ain 't as fast as you used to be , huh , Julius ?
Shit , Tony , bro , I didn 't know it was you .
What are you , mental ? How many times have I gotta tell you ?
I 'm Anthony . He 's Tony .
Oh , yeah . That 's Tony . That 's Tony . Right .
Well , you know , all you goombahs look alike to me .
Julius , Julius , Julius .
Tony .
- You got our money ? - Yeah , I got your money .
- Oh , shit . I had it just a minute ago . - Yeah , then you 're a minute too late .
- [ gun cocks ] - Tony , you don 't have to do that to me .
Tony , who 's gonna take care of my kids ?
- You don 't have any kids , asshole . - I 'll start .
Hey , don 't worry about it , Julius . Nobody 's going to miss you . Do it .
- [ man ] I wouldn 't do that if I were you . - What ?
You might miss the heart . Aim between the eyes
that way you get a nice , even spray .
- What the hell ? - Who the fuck are you ?
I 'm Maximillian , a connoisseur of death , you might say .
But no one seem to takes pride in the art anymore .
It 's so rare you come across a clean kill nowadays .
Oh , you 've got two seconds to beat it , eggplant ,
or you 're gonna share a coffin with Carl Lewis here .
- I already have a coffin of my own . - Come on .
He 's no fun . He fell right over .
There 's some fucking wackos in this town .
Let 's get back to you , Julius .
- I guess you 're out of bullets , huh ? - No , I kept one special just for you .
Interesting .
I have been stabbed , and I 've been hanged ...
and I 've been burned , even broken on the rack once ,
but I 've never been shot before .
It kind of itches a little .
You have quite decent aim though .
But next time ...
- [ gasps ] - [ flesh rending ]
[ snarling ]
Put a little heart into it .
Ouch .
[ gasps ]
[ moaning ]
- [ snarls ] - [ screams ]
- Fuck . Tony . Oh , shit . - [ bullets clattering ]
Don 't go away .
He 's going to give me the gun .
[ screams ]
- [ grunting ] - [ flesh rending and tearing ]
Oh , shit .
[ screaming ]
[ horn honking ]
He ain 't gonna get me .
I have seen enough . I have seen it all .
I 'm getting my ass the hell out of Brooklyn .
I 'm going down to the islands . Something peaceful , yeah .
Coney Island or Rikers Island or Devil 's Island .
- Let me light that for you . - Oh , shit .
Oh , shit . Oh , shit .
Oh , shit .
Hey , man . I don 't know how you know me , but ... everything is everything .
I ain 't seen nothing , okay ?
So you can just jump right back through the window .
Man , I won 't tell nobody I saw you ' cause I ain 't really seen you .
I 'm blind . I got , like , cataracts .
I mean , contacts . I got astigmatism , man .
I can 't see . I 'm blind . Where you at ? Where you at ? See , look .
Where you at ? Where you at ?
I saw you at the docks .
You 're a liar , a thief and a cheat .
No . That 's my brother , Miles . I 'm the honest one in the family .
Well , that 's unfortunate , because that 's what I liked about you .
Hey , easy , easy , bro . Hey , now , come on .
You ain 't got to pull that Blacula shit with me , all right ?
If you 're hungry , I 'll run you down to KFC and hit you off with a two-piece .
I already had Italian .
[ shouts ]
You 're going to make me think that you don 't like me .
Wouldn 't want to do that now , would we ?
I got nothing but love for you , baby .
Hey . What the fuck you doing ?
- Welcome to the party , Julius . - Oh , shit .
It hurts , doesn 't it ?
Yes , pain is an underrated experience , but it happens to be my specialty .
And like it or not , you belong to me now .
Hey , hey , bro . Why 'd you do that ?
It feels kind of ... kind of right .
Because I need your eyes in the day and your services at night .
But first I 'll need my coffin . Come .
Come .
Wait , where are you going ?
Hey , man . What 's up ?
You ain 't gonna be sucking my neck ?
Why would I do that ? You 're my ghoul now .
- I need you to help me find a woman . - A woman ?
You came to the right spot , man . I mean Brooklyn 's full of hos .
I 'm not interested in your hos .
I am looking for a special woman .
One of my kind , the only one like her in the world .
As I 've come to her , she 'll soon come to me like a moth to a flame .
So , you 're checking for a vampster bitch , huh ?
Half-vampire . And she 's ignorant of it .
The other half of her still sleepwalks in humanity .
But that 's nothing I cannot cure as long as I find her before the next full moon .
- Here ? - Yes , here .
Somewhere in Brooklyn .
[ siren approaching ]
[ man ] Oh , man , this night shift is kicking my ass .
How come you never get tired ?
I 've always been more of a night person myself .
Check it out . This is a good one . All right , listen up now .
" Your fate will be tested as a loved one dances with death .
- " Beware the dark stranger . " - Dark stranger .
" When all 's lost , look to your soul for the answers . "
I sure wouldn 't want to be you this week .
Hey , partner , that 's your horoscope , not mine .
That 's my horoscope ?
Oh , shit .
[ reporter ] Seventeen dead so far , apparently crew .
The ship was thought to be of Caribbean origin ...
- [ horn honks ] - [ helicopter approaching ]
We have no information as yet on the cause of death ,
but we have noticed that all bodies so far seemed drained of blood .
[ siren wailing ]
What the hell is this , captain ?
Love boat here came in a few hours ago .
There 's 18 that we know of . Whole gang 's DOA .
- Jeez . Ship 's log ? - Sort of .
It 's half-rotten and written in some strange language .
We sent it down to NYU to see if they could figure it out .
- Witnesses ? - Some night watchman over there
named Silas Green . Let him tell you what he thinks he saw .
- Find out what really happened . - All right .
- Hey , Rita . - Hey .
- How 's your new partner holding up ? - She 's cool , all right ?
- She just needs some time . - She 's had three months already .
Look , I know this is a rough time with her mother dying
in the nuthouse and everything . She 's got a job to do .
She 's a good cop . She 'll surprise you .
That 's what I 'm afraid of .
- I got it . It 's kind of narrow here . - Yeah , yeah .
- Watch your step , lady . - Excuse me .
Oh , my back is killing me . How many more we got ?
Fifteen of them left .
- Careful there . - Shit .
Give me your light .
You need a cast-iron stomach .
[ detective ] So you say you saw ... a what ?
It was a wolf , goddamn it . A big , black , stinking-ass wolf .
The motherfucker jumped off the boat and ran over there .
When it got there , son of a bitch turned into a man .
It did the flip-flop shit on me ,
just like a whore I knew in Detroit back in ' 62 , ' 63 .
I 'd go over her house on Saturday night ... Just love me , man .
Take her chicken and some pretzels .
I 'd come to the door . She 's a man !
Flip-floppin ' and shit !
You ever seen a motherfucker flip-flop on you and shit like that in your face ?
Going crazy and flipping and shit .
So , the wolf you saw looked something like that right there .
- What , the wolf ? - The wolf .
That ain 't look like that .
That 's a Chihuahua compared to the motherfucker that come at me .
You must be crazy .
- You seen The Wolf Man ? - Yeah .
To the 25th power .
You people belong behind the line .
- Hey , where 's your coffin at ? - My coffin is on the boat .
On the boat ? Shit , we can 't get it now .
Look at all these cops here . I 'm allergic to cops .
And you people . You people better keep back .
Killer loves to bite .
And so do I.
Jump .
Killer ?
- Here . Here , boy . - Oh , shit . Lovely , dude .
[ loud crash ]
[ flies buzzing ]
[ helicopter approaches ]
[ screaming ]
[ Maximillian ] Hello .
Someone here ?
[ heart beating ]
[ heartbeat increasing ]
[ creaking ]
[ screams ]
No !
It 's you .
[ screams ]
[ thunderclap ]
Is someone there ?
Shit . Damn it .
Wait .
- Hey , chill , chill . It 's just me . - Shit .
- Did you see him ? - There 's nobody here but us .
Someone 's here .
- I saw him or it . - It ?
What the fuck ? What 's wrong with you ?
There 's a coffin .
Okay . Come on . Right in there . Look .
What ? I don 't see anything .
Give me that .
- I could have sworn . - Rita , are you okay ?
I 'm fine , all right ? I 'm absolutely fine .
Good , ' cause that 's exactly what I told Captain Dewey .
That you were absolutely fine .
Right .
- Are you all right ? - I 'm getting out of here .
What is that ?
It 's an ear .
A rotted-off human ear .
[ Julius ] Yeah , but my ear , man ?
Would you look at this ? My fucking ear fell off .
- You ain 't said nothing about my ear . - You have another on the other side .
And besides , the benefits of being a ghoul far outweigh the drawbacks .
Benefits ? What benefits ? Benefit my fucking ear back on , man .
What , you put me in the monster union ?
I 'm on Blue Cross ... No , I meant Blue Shield . I meant Blue Shield , bro .
I 've taken refuge in some sorry places in my time .
But this one is a bargain . You ain 't gonna get a bargain like this .
- My uncle Silas is the landlord . - What the hell is all this damn noise ?
- Oh , shit . - Julius .
- Is that you ? - Yeah . It 's me . It 's me .
You little scared piece of shit .
I ought to whoop your ass for booking out on me like that .
- Sorry . - You wouldn 't believe the shit I 've seen .
I bet you I would , Unc .
Nobody believes me . I know a big-ass wolf when I see one .
What the hell 's going on ?
Just ...
- Who 's that ? - That 's my boss .
- You got a job ? - What you mean I got a job ?
I can 't have a job ? I got a job .
I 've got a good job too .
This cat got loot . He just needs a place to lay low .
Rent 's double .
- No . What ? - Triple .
- What ... - You know you missing an ear ?
Oh , shit . Hey , look . That 's just a trick I 'm working on .
I got to talk to you about the rent . You can 't triple the rent .
- [ coins clink ] - We got ...
Night started off like shit but end up pretty good .
See , I don 't turn nothing down but my collar .
How do you do , sir . Welcome to the neighborhood .
Trash man comes on Tuesday . God loves you . God loves me . Bye .
Hey , man . Good thing you ran into me because I can hook you up .
I 'll make sure that everything we do is going to be right .
But first of all , we in Brooklyn now , man . You got to get rid of this big-ass thing .
You ever heard of a futon ? They 're lighter , they 're comfortabler ,
they are better for your back .
You know , they even good to fuck on , man . This is bullshit here .
You 're gonna scratch your ass fucking on this . What 's the matter ?
[ Julius grunting ]
A couple of things to know .
- One , never sit on my coffin . - Okay .
- Two , I want to find the girl tonight . - Sounds good , yeah .
Is there a three ?
I don 't like mirrors .
Got it .
- [ Maximillian ] Rita . - [ gasps ]
Maybe I am going crazy .
[ breathing heavily ]
[ crashing , snarling ]
[ crashing , snarling continues ]
[ breathing heavily ]
[ groans ]
Mama , what 's happening to me ?
[ sirens wailing in distance ]
[ Rita ] Justice , it 's not just the bodies or the ear .
I got a strange feeling about this case .
Rita , you 've got a strange feeling about everything ,
and what do I say to you every time ?
I know what you say . Everything by the book .
But what if this ain 't in the book , huh ? Going by the book won 't solve it .
It might .
Come on , all I 'm saying is give something to intuition .
- Excuse me . - Hey , Captain .
If you two are finished , we got a development
in that boat people mess .
We 've got a couple of stiffs in a dumpster over on Bates Street .
- One guy was ripped to pieces . - Ripped to pieces ?
What about the other guy ?
Oh , he 's in one piece at least , except he 's missing a heart .
Bates Street . Two blocks from the docks .
- Very good . - Thank you .
What about the ship 's log ? We got anything on that ?
The university couldn 't make heads nor tails of it ,
so they sent it over to this Dr. Zeko , apparently some sort of specialist .
- Zeko . What 's the address ? - 315 South Rockaway .
315 South Rockaway ? That 's a tough neighborhood .
- What kind of doctor is this ? - I don 't know .
- Maybe he 's a heart specialist . - Come on . Let 's check it out .
- I didn 't get to finish my coffee . - Take it with you . Go , come on .
Zeko 's , huh ? Yeah , got me the 411 .
I got the info and a happy meal .
Mmm . Mmm .
Good .
[ Maximillian ] Things were progressing well .
Rita 's vision of herself dead in my coffin
was a certain sign she was destined to be my mate .
Even my ghoul was showing potential ,
performing well those duties only a ghoul can do
when the cursed sun drives a vampire to the shelter of his coffin .
In return , he would enjoy all the perks and pleasures of ghouldom ,
maybe even someday make vampire himself .
All with only the most minor of side effects .
Shit . What ? Hey . What ... What you ...
- What you doing sitting there , bro ? - You got the dropsies .
- That 's what I think . - I ain 't got no dropsies .
So , what you ... Tell me ... Tell me what you think of these wheels here .
I say lucky it 's an automatic .
You sure as hell don 't have enough hands to shift and drive at the same damn time .
- A wedding ? - A funeral .
- Very nice touch . - Come on . I knew you 'd like it .
I used to look like that in ' 62 .
- Same hair , same clothes . - There you go .
- Would you stop harassing him ? - If I was you , I 'd take a dick check .
It 's all there . It 's all there .
Thank God for small favors . And I do mean small .
See that ?
[ clucks tongue ] Young punk .
Hey , Max , let me ask you something .
Why didn 't you bite this bitch when you had the chance ?
It doesn 't work that way . She has to give herself to me voluntarily .
[ laughs ] Hey , this is Brooklyn , baby .
Don 't nobody give up shit unless you got some cold cash
or a hot slug for their ass .
In this case , I know more about her than she knows about herself .
One dance with me , one dance , and she 'll be mine .
Yeah . Now you 're talking , player . Now you 're talking . Take her dancing .
I bet you dance that old wild Hammer shit . Let 's put on some music .
Show me what you going to do when you get into your wild vampire self .
Show me that old Hammer shit you gonna do .
Go . That 's some good shit , man .
Am I gonna disappear in the mirrors too ? You can do that shit . It 's fly shit .
[ electrical crackling ]
I 'm warning you to drive the limo and shut your fucking mouth .
Shut up .
Hey , you can 't do that while I 'm driving .
Shut the fuck up .
- Shit . I 'm driving . - Goddamn it .
What the fuck ? Did you give me a brain aneurysm ? What was that ?
Damn , man . You can put somebody 's eye out like that .
So , I had the lab do a check on that seaweed that was all over the boat .
Seems that particular type only grows in an isolated area of the Caribbean .
Caribbean ? Hmm .
My mother did her studies down there somewhere before she had me .
Rita , how come you don 't talk about your mother much ?
The paper says she was an incredible woman .
There 's nothing to talk about . I never really knew her .
I mean , she sort of flipped out after she had me .
They stuck her in the institution , me in a foster home . That 's the end of the story .
How did your father handle it ?
He didn 't .
He was murdered down in the islands right before I was born .
I wish I had known him or at least something about him , but ...
- Wait a minute . - What ?
If we got the right address , that 's Dr. Zeko 's .
That 's a pretty funky doctor 's office .
[ reggae playing ]
♪ Very superstitious ♪
♪ Writings on the wall ♪
- So where is this con anyway ? - I don 't know .
- Closer than you think . - Dr. Zeko , I 'm Detective ...
I know who you are and why you 're here .
So you know where this ship originated from .
Any one of a hundred isles in the swells of the Sargasso Sea ,
in an area you call the Bermuda Triangle . Come on , sit down .
I 'm sorry . The Bermuda Triangle ?
Dr. Zeko , what does the log say ?
Spoke of a voyage filled with sickness and nightmares .
- They believed an evil was aboard . - An evil ?
I thought they killed the last of them , but these men warn us from beyond .
- He 's here . - He ?
Nosferatu . The undead .
Vampire .
Look , nothing personal , my man ,
but this is a murder investigation , not a witch hunt .
That boat 's crew are all sleeping at the morgue .
They are not cruising the boulevard sucking necks .
The world is full of false notions , detective .
Vampires are an exclusive race , not a club to be welcomed into
- merely because they 've been bitten . - Yeah , yeah , a race .
- Not a club . Of course . - Beware , detective .
What you 're facing is more deadly
than anything your profession has shown you .
A vampire has no mercy , no regrets .
He can change shapes .
He could be sitting right next to us right now , and we wouldn 't even know it .
Yeah , well , I would know it .
Rita , I 'm gonna call in , all right ?
[ Rita ] All right .
Dr. Zeko , how do you know so much about this ?
On my island ...
I faced one over a woman .
I lost .
She was taken .
Here 's my best advice , and please listen carefully .
[ hisses ]
Keep your faith , Rita .
If I know one thing , it 's this ...
- you 'll need it . - Yes .
Do you have a problem , pal ?
- There 's a killer on the loose . - You don 't say .
And what might you know about him ?
Well , he 's very smart and very quick and quite deadly .
And do you know where this killer is ?
He 's right behind you .
- [ hisses ] - [ screams ]
- Shit . - It 's all right .
- Oh , I 'm gonna die . - No , not quite yet .
- Oh , shit . - They 're very much like us , you see .
Misunderstood .
Sorry .
This never happened before .
Oh , my ...
That 's unbelievable . Thank God you were here .
Oh , God had nothing to do with it .
I 'm Max .
Rita . Rita Veder .
[ sounds fade out ]
[ heart beating ]
I think ...
You know , I know this is gonna sound like a line , but , uh ...
I really feel like I 've seen you somewhere before .
Do you believe in the supernatural ?
I might .
Well , I had this dream .
What kind of dream ?
There was a beautiful woman ...
a woman with a smile so lovely it could brighten the darkest night .
But she was trapped .
She was trapped in a prison where the moon never shined .
She couldn 't escape because she didn 't know how .
And then I came , and I set her free .
Did you ?
The woman was you , Rita .
I recognize you .
Well ...
How did you set me free ?
I set you free with a dance .
Let me show you .
Come .
[ sound returns to normal ]
What am I thinking ? I can 't . I 'm ... I 'm on duty .
You 're on duty ? Sounds like a personal problem .
We ain 't trying to hit at you . You know who this is ?
This ain 't Nick Ashford , baby . This is Maximillian . All right ?
This motherfucker 's got a pussy surplus , don 't you ?
Solid as a rock . Hey , hey . All right , fuck it then .
He 's trying to get his fuck on . He want to get it on with you , see ?
So , why don 't you just be nice , show my man some respect
' cause he 'll put it on you .
Hey , she 's straightened out . Come on . Let 's get out of here .
- I am sorry . - Oh , no .
Who knew you were so popular , huh ? But it 's a good thing
' cause I wouldn 't dance with your ass if you were the last man on earth .
- You ready ? - Yeah .
More than .
- I 'll see you again , Rita . - In your dreams , Max .
- She 's one of a kind . - She is .
Not your kind though .
Fuck them . They were made for each other .
[ gagging ]
This tongue of yours has complicated a very simple plan .
If it happens again , I 'll hang you with it . Do you understand ?
I have to take more drastic measures . My time is running short .
You 're the boss man . Shit .
[ Justice ] Rita , just give me a break .
Now you 're saying there 's some evil spirit stowed away on board ?
Hey , what if I am , huh ? Do you want cream ?
No . If Captain Dewey heard you , she 'd have you wrapped in a straitjacket .
Sometimes I feel things , all right ?
Now , I didn 't ask for it , I don 't understand it ,
but I do know you can 't always explain everything by the book .
You finally get a man back in the apartment
and you gonna kick his ass ? Interesting approach .
Justice , this is my roommate Nikki .
Nikki , my partner Justice .
Well , from the way y 'all was arguing , I 'd swear you was in love .
- Please . No . - No .
- Good . - I 'm gonna go on back to the crib
' cause it 's getting a little late .
- And ... - Wait a minute . You 're going ...
- You don 't want the coffee ? - No .
You can buy me some tomorrow .
I guess I 've had my fill of superstition for one night .
Next thing you know , we 'll be seeing little green men .
Right . Sure . Whatever , okay .
You can find your way out , right ?
[ Nikki ] You sure you don 't want coffee ? I 'll make you some .
No . I 'm breaking out . Who painted this ?
Oh , that 's Rita 's .
She paints things she sees in her nightmares .
Rita 's got weird taste in art , but good taste in men .
It 's real late . Got to go . Bye .
[ door opens , closes ]
[ Nikki ] You know what Freud would say .
If you leave something this important behind , it , uh ...
it means you really don 't want to go .
Whoa , hey , whoa .
Two words : cold shower .
Thank you .
[ Maximillian ] Now , he 's obviously a man of poor taste .
My sentiments exactly .
Ooh .
You sure ain 't from around here .
Yes , you could say I 'm a long ways from home .
Oh , well , uh ... mine 's upstairs .
Would you like to come and warm up with some coffee , or ...
some other refreshment ?
Well , I wouldn 't want to keep you up .
[ train wheels squeaking ]
[ light gasp ]
[ bedsprings squeaking ]
Oh , no .
Damn you , Justice .
Damn you .
I do not believe you .
I do not .
Oh , my God .
[ Nikki ] Let me see your face ! [ screams ]
[ snarls ]
- [ snarling ] - [ train wheels squeaking ]
[ snarling ]
[ distant howling ]
[ snarling laughter ]
[ groans ]
Nikki ?
[ Maximillian ] This part of the seduction is quite simple really .
You just take away everything that she has ,
then give her everything she needs .
[ Nikki ] Rita . Girl , I finally found a man who can make the room spin .
Moving out to find a place of my own
' cause we 're going to need the room to roam . Ciao , baby . Nikki .
Great .
[ Julius laughs ] Oh , yeah . You , like , figure out what she 's into
and then flip it and fuck her head up with it , huh ?
[ Maximillian ] In a manner of speaking , yes .
What church ? She had to go to a church .
Hey , man . My pops always said
the quickest way to a woman 's heart is through the church .
It 's actually through the rib cage , but that 's a bit messy .
No , Julius . There are much more interesting ways to her heart .
Through her fears , for instance , or through her faith .
[ bell tolling ]
- [ Maximillian ] Excuse me . - Excuse me for a second , sir .
- Preacher Pauley . - Yes . I 'm Preacher Pauley .
If you 've been misbehaving , Preacher Pauley 's here for saving .
Well ...
I think that I 'm beyond saving .
- You going to church ? - Yes . I just want to catch Preacher .
Is he still in the parking lot ?
Preacher Pauley . I 'm Preacher Pauley .
- Preacher Pauley . - Yes , how are you tonight ?
Rita , Rita Veder . How are you tonight , girl ?
I 've been tossing about this case that I 'm working on .
You 're tossing . Right .
I 've been having these really strange feelings .
- Strange feelings and tossing . - Yes .
And I just felt that I needed to talk to someone that I could trust .
Then you come to the right place . Come on .
You 're tossing and having strange feelings . And you 're tossing .
- And then I heard the voices . - Voices . You heard voices ?
Yes , like they were inside my head .
Voices you 've been hearing ?
Really . I mean , does this make sense ? Is any of this possible ?
Well , sister , you 'd be surprised at things that are possible .
I guess I 'm just afraid of ending up like my mother .
- Afraid I might be losing my mind . - You 're afraid you 're going crazy .
Good . I mean , it 's good to get that out . You can 't leave that inside .
If you feel you 're going crazy , tell people .
You gotta let it out . You need an outlet .
Well , actually , I get it out in my paintings .
- Oh , you paint . That 's interesting . - Yes .
- Good to paint . - Yes .
When I was young , I used to paint ...
Preacher Pauley , come on now . Everybody 's waiting .
- Well , I don 't know right now ... - Go ahead , Preacher .
- I 'm talking to the young lady . - The Lord waits for no one .
- Get your butt in here . - Right now is not a good time .
[ gasps ]
Goddamn .
What did he say ?
God damn anybody who doesn 't glorify in his work .
It 's a hell of a night outside . Let 's do the sermon on the lawn .
Come on , sister . Goddamn . Shit .
Excuse me .
♪ ... Go marching in ♪
♪ O Lord , I want to be in that number ♪
Can we bring it down just a little bit , please ? Can we bring it down ?
Brothers and sisters , please quiet down . Thank you .
[ congregants humming ]
Brothers and sisters , we 've come here time after time ,
and we talk about the same old same old .
- Quiet . - [ humming stops ]
- We talk about Jesus . - Yes , that 's right .
- Jesus said and Jesus went . - Oh , yes .
- Jesus heard and Jesus walked over it . - [ congregants assenting ]
- Jesus , Jesus , Jesus . - [ assenting ]
I don 't want to talk about Jesus this evening .
' Cause as the big man teaches us , there 's two sides to every story .
Not one but two .
A story is not one-sided .
A story has duality .
There 's two sides to every story .
What brings to mind the phrase " necessary evil . "
I know many of you may hear the phrase , " necessary evil , " and you say ,
" That don 't even make no sense to me . Can 't be no such thing .
How 's evil necessary ? That don 't match .
That 's plaids and stripes , evil and necessary . "
You see , because without bad , there is no good .
Without light , there is no dark . You need both these things .
Do you hear what I 'm saying ?
- If every day is a sunny day ... - Yes , yes !
Well , then what 's a sunny day ?
Well , the bottom line , brothers and sisters ,
what I 'm trying to tell you tonight is that evil ...
evil is necessary .
Evil is necessary . Thereby , if it 's necessary , evil ...
- [ congregants ] Evil . - Must be good .
Evil is good .
That 's what I think . Evil must be good .
- Let me hear you all say it . - Evil is good .
That 's right . Evil is good .
Take Brother Brown , for instance ,
one of our strongest deacons , pillar of stability .
Brother Brown was down on Buttrick Avenue last night
- with a two-dollar ho . - [ congregants gasping ]
Oh , please , baby . I didn 't know she was no ho .
You stinking dog ! You told me you was at your mama 's .
Now that 's evil .
When you tell your wife , " I 'm going to see Mama , "
then you go on Buttrick Avenue and get you a two-dollar ho , that 's evil .
But Brother Brown had a good time with that two-dollar ho .
You can push a two-dollar ho to the line . She don 't have no limits .
Evil and good , they walk hand in hand .
Evil is as evil does .
Rita , hey , I thought I 'd find you here .
What are you doing here ?
The captain wants us to check something out .
She got info on those two stiffs in the dumpster .
- What 's wrong with you ? - [ Maximillian ] Remember Nikki .
- You fucked her , didn 't you ? - We got us another one .
- Fucked who ? - You know damn well who . Nikki .
- You know damn well who . - What ?
Nikki . The whore of Babylon . That 's what she was .
The whore of Babylon .
- Rita , I never touched that girl . - Oh , yeah ?
Then you should change shirts more often . That 's her lipstick on your collar .
Lipstick on his collar . What kind of man are you ?
- It 's a shame and it 's shocking . - Rita , it didn 't happen like that .
Tell her it didn 't happen that way .
Don 't be ashamed , boy . Ain 't nothing wrong with that .
Don 't be ashamed because you went out and got you a little ass .
Ass is good .
I know many of y 'all may be saying ,
" How does the preacher say ass is good ? " How do y 'all think y 'all got here ?
If it wasn 't for ass , you wouldn 't be here . Ass is good .
Evil is good , and ass is good , and if you get you a piece of evil ass ...
Whoo !
Rita , where you going ? Rita , you bugging .
- This is ridiculous , Rita . - If it 's so damn ridiculous , forget it .
Let 's not forget it . I left right after you went to bed .
You ain 't got to explain .
No , I 'm explaining it because she bumped into me .
I spent the night at the station . There 's five guys that can swear to that .
Hey , what do I know ? She borrows everything else of mine .
Of yours ?
Did you say yours ?
- That came out wrong . - No . You said yours .
No , no . Forget it . It doesn 't matter .
You got your own rules , you play by your own game .
Rita , you and I , we see things different .
We know that . But that don 't have to be a bad thing .
It just means we have a lot to learn from each other .
Now , look , the reason I came here
is because I got a line on those two John Does . Guess what .
- What ? - They worked for Kitty Caprisi .
[ thunderclap ]
- The mob boss ? - Bingo .
Now , it 's getting ready to rain . You want to get in the car ?
[ sighs ]
[ clapping and singing , indistinct ]
Heads up , y 'all .
Get out of here , you piece of shit .
You ain 't got the balls for this kind of work , Guido .
You made your point . Need to tell you something .
I could be a good stickup man , Bear . I 'm the fucking best , all right ?
Hey , there 's a hot piece of ass .
You kiss your mama with that mouth ?
I didn 't know she was with somebody . Excuse me . Excuse the grabbing .
- I 'm sorry . I don 't want no trouble . - Get out of here .
- Angelo , you do me a favor ? - Get the fuck out of here , Guido .
I 'm out of here . I 'm going , all right ?
Oh , shit . You should get an Oscar for that shit .
You the man , boy .
One minute , you 's you , and the next minute , bam .
You change yourself into AI Sharpton .
- Like taking candy from a child . - Can you teach me to do that shit ?
It takes a master vampire to transform oneself into a human ,
especially to absorb their thoughts . You have such messy minds .
Boss , I got an idea .
Go change yourself into her partner . That 'll fuck her head up .
The ones that I go into , there must first be a doorway of evil .
I 've yet to discover such a thing with this man , Justice .
- Frankly , it 's beginning to annoy me . - Yeah . Me too .
" Ristorante Italiano . "
Perfetto . If one is going to wine and dine a woman ,
he must know what to wine and dine her with .
But she 's in there with that toy cop .
Yes , and after I take her order , we are all going for a ride together .
That 's what I 'm talking about . It 's about time . Let 's heat it up .
Go in there and rip off his head and shit down his neck , boss .
- Act like a vampire . - Where did you get that ?
This ? Oh , that 's from Bloomingdale 's .
I kicked in a window and took it off one of the white mannequins
standing there like this . I figure I can use it more than he can .
You 're improvising . That 's very good . You 're turning into my best ghoul ever .
Get your fucking hands up , Sambo . Now get over here .
- Move your ass , all right ? - Take my hand . It 's all I got .
You take that fucking hand , you shove it up your ass , Meadowlark .
Are you a magician ? You got a dove in there ?
Give me your fucking wallet . All your money . Come on .
- Brooklyn . - Come on .
- I love this place . - Jesus .
Oh , you fucking moolie bastard !
Dumbass .
[ crunching ]
They was making a pickup on , let 's just say , some business proceeds .
- Pickup from who ? - Just a punk numbers runner ,
name of Julius something or other .
I seen his girlfriend kick the living snot out of him once .
Some big broad named Eva , lives down on Court , I think .
So you think this Julius could have iced your boys ?
- Iced the boys . - That putz couldn 't ice tea .
He 's almost as big a chickenshit as Guido .
Hey , Bear .
Okay , drop your shit on the floor . Nobody be smart .
Put your guns on the floor right now . Everybody . Come on .
Everybody . Let 's go . You , empty the cash register right now .
Hurry up . Do it .
Okay , here we go .
Hey , there 's a lot of fucking love in this room . Look at this .
Speaking of which , do you believe in love at first sight , darling ?
- Get the hell away from me . - Trying to play hard to get .
I 'll work on you for a while . Watch it , John Shaft .
I 'll put a hole in your Afro . You 're gonna be my new girlfriend .
Come on . Here we go . Let 's keep this moving .
Is that register empty ? What 's with this ?
Get rid of this garlic . It 's all over the fucking place .
Hold the fucking garlic bread .
The next person to offer a fucking garlic product
is going to get one in the ass , all right ?
You tell that fucking cat to shut the fuck up , or I 'll whack him .
I 'm fucking starving . You wanna get some takeout ?
Let 's get some takeout . What 's your favorite pasta ?
- Fusilli . - Mine too .
We need some pasta here . Fusilli . You , garlic boy .
- Okay . - Get her some fusilli . Two to go .
- Move your ass . - It 's coming .
Jesus Christ . Fucking music is making my ears bleed in here .
We need some wine . What kind ?
- Red . - Joey , red wine . Come on .
Move your ass . This place is making me itch in here .
- Sugar ! - Hey , hey .
The fucking cat has it coming to him .
He 's been fucking hissing and making claws since I came in .
Hey .
- [ grunts ] - [ groans ]
- Son of a bitch . I 'll kill him . - I like cats .
Well , that 's all you had to say , dollface .
Ow , ow . All right , not so tight , Mr. Tibbs .
Hey , lover , you 're coming with me , all right ?
I 'm going with her , okay ? I 'm going with you . Let 's go .
- Hey , Bear , who 's got the balls now ? - Fuck you .
[ all shouting , indistinct ]
Back off .
Motherf ...
- You always got to be the hero . - It was just an impulse , okay ?
This guy had a fucking .38 to your head . He could 've killed you .
Hey , not a .38 . It was a .45 . I resent that , all right ?
- Shut up . - Hey , I know you .
Did I see you over at Jugs on Fifth Street , that titty bar , the other night ?
- Shut up . - Look , I brought him down , didn 't I ?
- Why can 't you just give me that ? - Because he 's an asshole . That 's why .
- [ both ] Shut up ! - I 'm quiet .
You were out of line .
You know damn well , you should have waited for me .
She don 't need you , Soul Train . You tell him , darling .
Shut up . Look .
I happened to be at the right place at the right time . No big deal .
The city of Brooklyn shall be judged as the city of Babylon .
It says here . Listen .
She bears a golden cup filled with her abominations
and the filth of her fornication .
We are supposed to be partners .
We 're supposed to look out for one another .
- But you just don 't get it , do you ? - Get what ? What are you talking about ?
I care about you a little more than I 'm supposed to .
But I can 't help that .
Nikki . That 's where I know you from .
Nikki , the girl from Bed-Stuy .
She told me some cop named Justice came by the other night and beast-fucked her .
The other night , that was you ?
- You 're the beast that fucked Nikki . - Will you shut the fuck up ?
It was you . You beast-fucked her . You did it . You know you did it .
- Rita , I don 't know what he 's talking ... - [ colleagues groaning ]
Detective Veder , I want you in my office right now .
You did good , honey . You did good . He 's an asshole .
He deserved every piece of that palm that hit his face . He deserved it .
Hey , hey . Take it easy , tough . What 's the matter with you ?
- Hey , police brutality . - Do something with this motherfucker .
Soul Train , me and you , right now , huh ?
You been informed of your rights , asshole ?
- Two-day suspension . - What ? Two days ?
Yes . I 've been informed of everything that I need to know .
- Another nutcase . All right . Move it . - Hey .
Try and kill the cop .
Yes .
Sinner ! Sinner ! Sinner !
What the hell is wrong ...
- He went that way . - He went that way ?
Yes , there .
Why don 't you guys do a job , huh ? Quit standing .
What are we doing on the floor ?
Rita .
- [ honking ] - [ gasps ]
Watch out .
Idiot .
[ cabbie ] Hey , watch where you 're going , lady .
You all right ?
Yeah . Thanks .
Jeez . Sunday drivers .
Hey .
- You 're ... - Mr. Popular .
But my friends call me Max .
- Well , I 'm ... - Rita . I remember .
I was just going by and you looked like you could use a hand .
- You 're bleeding . - Oh . I 'll live .
You know , that 's twice I owe you .
- You always got to be the hero ? - Oh , I ...
just happened to be in the right place at the right time . It 's no big deal .
Hmm .
- Look , the bar thing , you know ... - Oh , that was my fault .
- No . - That was my fault . I apologize .
- My friend was drunk that night . - No . It was ...
Really , it was one of those days , you know ?
Kind of like today .
I understand . I 'm actually more of a night person myself .
Really ?
- So am I. - Mm .
Well ...
I ... I better get going .
I 'm ... I 'm starving too .
Thanks . Good night .
Good night .
Do you like Italian ?
I make an excellent fusilli .
[ chuckles ]
Actually , that 's my favorite ,
but I really think I ought to take a rain check .
Oh . There 's someone else .
No .
Not anymore .
Well , if there 's no one else , then I would love to have you for dinner .
Look here . I 'm a cop .
- The police . - Mm-hmm . The law .
Which means if you try anything funny , I 'll shoot you .
Do I look like I would bite you ?
[ chuckles ]
You better not , not after the day I 've had .
Can I send my car to pick you up in a half hour ?
Oh ... Your car .
Well , then , let 's make it an hour .
I 'll see you then .
[ footsteps receding ]
Look , Rita ...
I just got a few things I need to say ' cause this is real hard for me and ...
Shit . I never said nothing like this before or nothing ...
Damn .
Look , I 'm the man ,
and I got a few things I got to set your ass straight on .
Right now , you 're going to do what I say to do .
[ laughs ] Shoot . I must be crazy .
- I know I ain 't gonna say that shit . - Justice ?
- Rita ? - So , what are you doing here ?
I , um ... was just ...
Where you going ?
Oh , dinner .
- Dinner . Dressed like that ? - Yeah .
- Who you going with ? - A friend .
A girlfriend .
I 'm just saying , because , damn , you look good .
- Can I give you a ride or something ? - [ loud music approaching ]
- I 've got one . Thanks . - Damn , that 's your ride ?
- Miss Rita . - Good eve ...
- Good evening . - Good evening .
Got to go .
Oh , did you want something ?
I , uh ... I was just going to get a pizza , and , you know , I thought ...
- Just have a good time , that 's all . - Thanks .
- Enjoy your dinner . - Yeah . You too .
You thought you was gonna get some ass tonight , didn 't you ?
Take your ass to Blockbuster , get a video .
Pizza place .
Ain 't no pizza place around here , you lying motherfucker .
[ cackling laughter ]
See ya . You need to lighten up , standing there looking all mean .
Get your lying ass out of the street .
[ cackles ]
- [ Rita ] Are you sure this is it ? - [ Julius ] Yeah , that 's it . Very low pro .
Right down that hall to the right .
[ Maximillian ] A minute earlier , she 'd have caught me casting every spell I knew
on Julius ' pigsty of an apartment ,
but by the time she arrived , I had the place in reasonable shape ,
if I do say so myself .
[ piano playing ]
[ chuckles ]
Please excuse the rest of my building . I only recently acquired it .
- This is incredible . - No . You 're incredible .
- You look fabulous tonight . - Thank you .
I don 't get to dress up too often .
Well , that needs to change . Do you like red wine ?
Oh , of course . It 's the only one I drink .
Really ? We share similar taste .
Van Gogh . He 's my favorite painter .
Oh , have a closer look .
- Is that the original ? - Yes .
He 's my favorite as well .
So torn by visions that no one else around him could appreciate .
You know , I find myself strangely drawn to his art .
It 's sort of an outlet for me .
I know what you mean .
- It 's beautiful . - Yes , it is .
To the beauty ...
of the night .
[ knocking ]
[ woman ] Hey , right here . I got it for you .
- [ Eva ] Go away . - Police officer .
Just want to ask you a few questions , ma 'am .
What the hell you trying to do ? Break my damn door down ?
Let me see your shield , not like it 's gonna mean shit .
Just want to ask you about a friend of yours , goofy-looking guy ,
used to be a numbers runner for Kitty Caprisi .
Julius ? He in trouble ?
Come on in .
[ Rita ] I feel as if you know me .
[ Maximillian ] Yes , we do have a great deal in common , don 't we ?
[ Rita ] Well , some things , yes , but ...
I mean , you 've been to so many places .
You 've seen so much . I mean , you 've had such an exciting life .
You might say that I 've had several .
[ " No Woman , No Cry " playing ]
You know , sometimes I wonder what 's out there ,
beyond the skyline , beyond Brooklyn .
Past everything I 've ever known .
Well , there 's no place you can 't go .
No place the subway doesn 't run .
But what about your dreams , Rita ?
Your dreams of another life and another world , another you ?
Everyone has those sorts of dreams .
You have a hunger never satisfied ...
and a need never fulfilled .
God only knows what I need .
And I know .
You need to give me this drink , give me your hand ,
- and come dance with me . - Oh , no .
- I 'm not a good dancer . - Oh , come , please . Just one dance .
Come , come .
Oh , Max .
Oh , this is crazy .
There 's nothing wrong with being just a little crazy .
♪ No woman , no cry ♪
♪ Woman , no woman , no cry ♪
♪ Woman , no cry ♪
♪ No woman , no cry ♪
♪ Woman , no woman , no cry ♪
I 've never danced like this before .
And now you 'll never stop .
I haven 't felt like this since ...
God , I 've never felt like this .
How would you like to feel like this every night ?
Is that a trick question ?
To go to places you 've never been ?
Yes .
Drink the wine you 've never tasted ?
I can give it to you , Rita .
A world where no one laughs at you for what you feel ...
what you see , what you are .
All you have to do is just ...
say it .
Say the word . Say it .
Yes .
[ moaning ]
Yes !
[ rap music playing ]
Shit .
Looking for the girl ?
Girl ? What girl ?
You 're a cop . You 're supposed to remember faces .
The night watchman , down at the dock , right ?
Right .
And I 'm also the proud landlord of this residential-type place ,
so I do know who come , and I do know who goes .
I 'm looking for a brother named Julius . Julius Jones .
Jones .
Knew a La Toya Jones once .
Used to call her Mrs. Butterworth ' cause she had an ass flat like a pancake .
I haven 't seen her around lately . But I have seen your partner .
Yes , I have .
- You 've seen my partner ? - Mm-hmm .
Must have done some serious bumping last night with that cat .
What cat ?
Some suave motherfucker . New tenant .
He 's been tapping that top-shelf booty .
I 'm talking about bang , bang , bang , bang .
She walk out here this morning , she was bowlegged .
So , you know where she went ?
Well ... [ chuckles ]
I 'd say she 's going home to get some sleep .
Of course , now , she didn 't get none last night .
Bang , bang , bang ...
[ policewoman on radio ] Thirteen Fox , come in , over .
- Shit . - Justice , where are you ?
Thirteen Fox . What 's up ?
We got a DOA at Brooklyn City Hall . Female , late 20s .
Captain requests you on the site .
- Hey , lieutenant . - Hey .
God knows who or what got her up there .
[ Justice ] Let me see that thing .
Looks like a bed sheet or something she 's wrapped up in .
Shit .
Damn . Nikki .
Rita .
[ Maximillian ] if there 's one thing a vampire has , it is patience .
Especially with those of his own kind .
Rita .
But even that , in time , runs out , and then in the family of darkness ,
blood will prove thicker than water can ever be .
Rita , wake up .
Rita , wake up . Wake up .
Justice ?
Damn , girl , I must have called here 50 times . What , you sleep all day ?
I 'm thirsty .
What 's going on ? What are you doing here ?
It 's about Nikki .
[ sighs ]
Look , Justice , whatever happened between you and her ...
She 's dead , Rita .
What ?
But it 's more than that .
The way she was hanging ...
it was exactly the way you painted it .
No .
No . No . It was ... It was just a dream .
No . It 's real .
Everything that you believed in and I didn 't is real .
Justice , you saw her ?
Oh . [ sobbing ]
Somehow , I 'm not crazy .
No . No crazier than the rest of us .
But why me ?
- Why is this happening to me ? - I don 't know .
But we 'll figure this out . Together .
Now , we make mistakes , and we have differences , but ...
It 's okay . We 're only human , right ?
Oh , Nikki .
[ sobbing continues ]
Rita .
- You know what you 're doing ? - Mm .
I 'll make it up as I go .
I want this , but ...
But damn . Oh , damn .
[ Justice groans ]
[ Maximillian cackling ]
[ laughs ]
[ growls ]
[ cackling continues ]
No !
- No ! No ! - Rita .
[ shouting ]
[ tires screeching , horn honking ]
Forget you , bitch !
[ humming ]
[ Rita whimpering ]
- Uh-oh . - Max !
Easy . Hold on , honey lamb .
Now ain 't a good time to fuck with the man , okay ?
Oh , shit .
- Oh , shit . He got you too ? - I 'll handle this .
Yeah , handle your business . I 'll be in the kitchen . Want a cappuccino ?
Welcome home , Rita . Do you still take red ? Wait , after last night ,
you 're probably wanting something with a little more bite .
- What have you done to me ? - I only did what you asked .
I didn 't ask for this !
Oh , but you wanted it . You needed it .
And now you can feel it . Look at you .
You 're more alive than you 've ever been , Rita . Stop fighting it .
- Death becomes you . - It was you , wasn 't it ?
All the murders , the alley , the boat , Nikki .
It 's a gift , but you have the same thing too .
- I just unwrapped it for you . - Gift ? Of what ? Death ?
Of life . I have given you eternal life .
No .
- This isn 't happening . - Oh , it 's happening right now .
Speak . Can you feel it ? Come on . Come here . Listen .
Listen to me . Do you hear that ? Do you hear it ?
- [ distant howling ] - That is the sound of the night .
It 's calling .
- Not to me . Not to me . - Yes .
Women .
[ siren wails in distance ]
- Frightening ... - [ shrieks ]
isn 't it ?
- You are . - I meant freedom .
To do anything you want , anytime , anywhere .
I know it 's terrifying at first .
I passed " terrified " about half an hour ago .
Rita .
All your life you wondered why you felt things that no one else felt .
Why you never caught a cold . Never broke a bone .
This is just a dream , right ? Pretty soon , I 'm going to wake up and ...
And I will be there .
Rita , I 'm not going to be alone again .
I 'd perish without you .
I can go back .
Go back ... to my life .
You can 't stop me .
You can 't .
Then go .
Go back to your little shoebox apartment filled with those empty dreams , huh ?
And go back to your church . Don 't forget the collection plate .
Your preacher 's whiskey supply is running low .
And go back to your job
where they laugh at you behind your back , and they call you crazy , or ...
you face the truth , Rita .
That you have no place left to go but to me .
What do you know about truth , huh ?
You lied to me from the beginning .
Your father sent me to you .
- What ? - That 's the truth .
Your father .
If I had told you that when I first met you , when I had come to you ,
if I told you what you were ...
would you believe me if I had told you that you were the daughter of a vampire ?
You 're lying !
You would have loved your father .
Your mother did before they killed him .
Who ? Who killed him ? Who ?
Humans . Humans fear what they don 't understand .
And they hate what they fear .
Your father sacrificed himself so your mother could survive .
That 's what drove your mother insane .
But what if I don 't ... want this ?
Rita .
What if you do ?
- [ screaming ] - [ laughing ]
[ man chanting in foreign language ]
[ speaking foreign language ]
[ chanting continues ]
[ stops speaking ]
Who 's there ?
Step into the light .
Ah , Detective Justice .
You were expecting me ?
You or the dark one .
Could have gone either way . Personally , I 'm glad it 's you .
I need your help .
Ooh ...
Things have changed . Come on . Sit down .
Rita has changed .
She 's ... She 's seeing things in her dreams .
- Now she 's missing . - What kind of dreams ?
Nightmares . She paints them .
A girl was murdered , and it was exactly the way Rita painted it .
And then ...
then I saw this .
It was the last one she did .
Then it 's true . There was a child .
I knew Rita 's mother , detective .
I was in love with her years ago .
She studied the vampires of my island . I was her guide .
I saw her succumb to the powers of the dark one , and Rita is the result .
[ woman ] It 's like , just please clean my house .
I don 't wanna hear that your kid 's sick .
- Max , please don 't . - We must do it .
Besides , she richly deserves it .
We must feed , Rita , or we die .
Well , here 's my shortcut .
- Bye-bye . - Bye .
[ Zeko ] This one that has come is the last .
He needs her . He has to move very , very quickly .
- I 'll kill him if he hurts her . - You have to .
If you want to save her , you must kill him
before she abandons her humanity and feeds .
Much as she is human , she 's now also a predator .
[ dog yipping ]
[ distant howling ]
What 's a nice girl like you doing in a place like this ?
I have pepper spray , and I swear I 'll use it .
But I want you to know , I understand the Negro people .
I understand how you 've been chained down
by the oppression of white capitalist society .
Yes , well ,
then you 'll understand this .
- Max . - [ yelping ]
- [ Maximillian snarling ] - [ flesh rending ]
No !
[ gasping ]
Your turn , Rita .
Taste her . Taste her and quench the hunger .
No .
- I won 't do it . - You don 't have a choice .
No deposit , no return . No going back .
- Help me . - No .
No .
I 'm not going forward .
You can 't run from your hunger , Rita .
There 's no place you can hide !
[ thunderclap ]
Forgive us our trespasses as we forgive those who trespass against us .
And lead us not into temptation ,
but deliver us from evil .
Help me .
- Where are you taking me ? - You need your rest .
- We have a long journey ahead of us . - Where are we going , boss ?
We go home , and while she rests , you pack .
We 'll try to leave by dawn .
- Can I talk to you about my head ? - Drive !
- Ready my coffin . We 're leaving . - Now ?
She don 't look like she ready . She need a nap .
I 'm going to ready the coffin . We can leave . We 're getting the fuck out of here .
Rita .
My sweet , you must feed or you 're going to die .
I want to die .
I won 't let you .
I 'll find someone for you .
[ Silas ] Hey , hey , hey . The Knicks won .
Julius , goddamn it , you owe me $ 50 .
Good God , he 's a bad motherfucker .
Julius . Where 's my $ 50 , Jul ...
You ain 't Julius .
You 're that cop 's girl . What 's wrong , baby ? You look sick .
Had too much pork today , huh ? Bad pig feet , ate the bay leaf .
Want some cod-liver oil , baby ? Tell me what you need .
What she needs is some fresh blood .
Blood ? Blood ? I 'll go to the Red Cross . Get all you need .
Shut up .
- Ouch ! Hey , brother , what 's the idea ? - The idea is dinner .
Dinner ? I don 't see no dinner . What we having ?
- You . - Me ? Don 't do it , baby .
Do it , Rita . You don 't have to resist . Do it .
Don 't do it . I got old , tired , grandpapa blood .
I got high blood pressure , baby . High as the motherfucking moon .
You suck my blood ...
Rita , no !
Police . Police .
- It 's okay . - Get out of my way . Police !
Rita , it 's all over . Just walk away .
- Hey , coffin 's all ready . - Take care of that one .
I got him . All right , super cop .
Better take your uncle and get the fuck out of here ,
or I 'm getting ready to put this shit on you .
- You better shut up . - Here I come . Oh , you 're not afraid .
[ shouting ]
That was my fucking eye .
Come back here . Shit .
You 're quite a bulldog , Justice , but Rita belongs to me now .
Motherfuck you , man .
Shit .
The heart .
This is my stomach . This is my heart .
You should know the rules , Zeko .
No .
Not him .
Rita !
Rita .
Are you okay ?
My leg . I think he broke my leg .
Fuck your leg . Have you seen my eye ? Easy .
- I 'm just looking for my eye . - Your eye ?
- Yeah , it came out my head . - I think I got your ear .
Damn . I said , " Watch your step , " nigga , shit .
You done mashed my shit all up .
- Coast clear ? - Yeah .
- You sure ? - Yeah . Give us a hand .
- I got to find an eye doctor . - I want y 'all to get out of here , man .
And get him to a hospital . I 'm not leaving without Rita .
Justice , remember the painting .
If she joins with him completely ,
- she 'll strike you next . - I 'd let that booty go .
The bitch tried to suck me like I 'm a damn 40 ounce of malt liquor .
- Kill him . - Thanks , doc .
God is with you .
I 'll keep that in mind .
- You 're going to need him . - All right , come on , man .
- I 'm going to get you out too . - I ain 't going nowhere .
My homey 's in there . He taking care of me .
- Taking care of you ? - Yeah .
Have you seen yourself lately ?
- Let 's get the hell out . - Don 't do that .
Look at this shit , man . Look at this shit .
- That 's my arm . - He taking care of you ?
- Put that back on . - Now you 're The Fugitive .
I ain 't no fugitive . Well , put that back on .
That 's my shit . I need this shit , man . You can 't just snatch a brother 's arm .
[ heart beating ]
Right through your black heart .
You shouldn 't have come .
- Rita . - It 's too late for me .
Rita ... Oh , shit . Look at you .
Now it 's too late for you .
Still don 't believe in vampires , detective ?
I 'm taking Rita with me . It 's not too late for her .
You should be worried about yourself .
- Hey , bitch . - Rita , get away from him .
I can give her everything , Justice . Tell me why you deny her that .
She doesn 't belong in your world . She 's not a killer .
- It 's in her blood . - But not in her heart .
It 's not in your heart , Rita .
- Are you sure about that ? - I 'm sure you 're ugly .
Come , you bastard .
Shit .
[ Justice shouting , grunts ]
That 's it . Goddamn it .
Idiot .
Get the fuck away from that knife . Get ... Come here .
Not in her heart , you say ? Why don 't you ask her what she is ?
I 'm hungry .
Tell him , Rita . Is his blood good enough ?
He 'll do just fine .
- Rita , no . - Forget it , Justice .
Time 's up . It 's too late .
It 's much too late .
This is your destiny .
And yours .
- Take him . - A part of me loves you so much .
But that part of me must die .
It must die .
[ screaming ]
I told you ...
that you were ...
a killer .
[ whimpers ]
[ crunching and rumbling ]
Come on , Rita . Let 's go .
Come on .
Come on . Get up . Come on , come on .
Get out . Come on .
I 'll take care of you . Let 's go .
- You 'll be okay . - No !
[ screaming ]
Where did it all ...
You did good , Rita .
You okay ?
Cross my heart ...
and hope to die .
- Come on . Let 's go . - I warned you , James .
I got to find myself a safer job , like the motherfucking bomb squad .
Hey , Unc , hey , at least you got your health .
Well , thank you .
And at least you got your , uh ...
Well , you know , you got , uh ... [ stammering ]
You got a limo .
- That 's right . I got a limo . - Mm-hmm .
- I got the front seat now . Let me drive . - Hey , great .
No more driving limos for me . Yeah , my little ass is in the back .
- Ooh ... - [ Julius laughing ]
Look at this bad mother here .
- Hey , Unc , talk to me . - Cruise control .
Power steering . Power brakes . Power windows . Power seats .
- And we 're surrounded by leather . - Let 's see what we got here .
Hey , look at ... Hey . Brother lost his mood ring .
Oh , shit . No .
No , man . This is Max 's shit .
Yeah , well , Max ain 't gonna need this .
Max is spread out all over Brooklyn . You know what I 'm gonna do ?
I 'm going to wear this in great Max 's honor .
You know , we got to represent our homey , the vampire .
Hey , Unc , check it out .
- GQ or what , nigga ? - Macaroni . Macaroni .
[ gasping ]
Jesus , Mary and Little Bo-Peep 's mama . What the hell 's wrong with you , Julius ?
Ain 't no smoking in the limo , Julius .
Good God almighty .
You done flip-flopped to end all the flip-flopping .
Unc , I got my shit back , man . I got my hand back .
I got my arm back . I got jewels out the ass .
Look at these jewels . Look at these fly-ass shoes I got , man .
- Oh , my . - What ?
Oh , my .
Man , Max said being a ghoul had benefits .
- What ? - But goddamn .
- Well , I ain 't no ghoul . - Welcome to the party , Unc .
Now let 's get this show on the road .
- Well , you 're the boss . - That 's right .
There 's a new vampire in Brooklyn .
And his name is Julius Jones .
I ever tell you about the time I won the Indianapolis 500 ?
- I beat a man called A. J. Fittipaldi . - Oh , yes .
- Yeah , I looked just like that in ' 62 . - Sixty-two ?
- Oh , they called me Pretty Willy . - Stop it , Pretty Willy . Drive the limo .
Oh , goddamn it .
[ Julius howling ]
[ Stevie Wonder 's " Superstition " performed by UB40 playing ]
♪ Very superstitious ♪
♪ Writings on the wall ♪
♪ Ladders ' bout to fall ♪
♪ Thirteen-month-old baby ♪
♪ Broke the lookin ' glass ♪
♪ Seven years of bad luck ♪
♪ Good things in your past ♪
♪ When you believe in things ♪
♪ That you don 't understand ♪
♪ Then you suffer ♪
♪ Superstition ain 't the way ♪
♪ Very superstitious ♪
♪ Wash your face and hands ♪
♪ Rid me of the problems ♪
♪ Do all that you can ♪
♪ Keep me in a daydream ♪
♪ Keep me goin ' strong ♪
♪ You don 't wanna save me ♪
♪ Sadie my song ♪
♪ When you believe in things ♪
♪ That you don 't understand ♪
♪ Then you suffer ♪
♪ Superstition ain 't a way ♪
♪ Very superstitious ♪
♪ Nothin ' more to say ♪
♪ The devil 's on his way ♪
♪ Thirteen-month-old baby ♪
♪ Broke the lookin ' glass ♪
♪ Seven years of bad luck ♪
♪ Good things in your past ♪
♪ When you believe in things ♪
♪ That you don 't understand ♪
♪ Then you suffer ♪
♪ Superstition ain 't the way ♪